- We will now begin a redemption round.
- What?
Are you serious?
Team KAIST's Jeon Ji-min.
I'll go with Pixel Cards 3, 7, and 8.
- That is correct.
- I'd hate to face Ji-min in another game.
The answer is...
I'll go with Pixel Cards 2, 4, and 6.
I'll go with Pixel Cards 1, 3, and 9.
- That is correct.
- How is he pulling it off?
- He beat four people all by himself.
- He's amazing.
As the winner of the redemption round,
Team KAIST secured a second chance.
They can rejoin the surviving teams
and compete in Elite League Season 3.
They really made it back from hell.
Good luck, guys.
- Let's do this.
- Good luck to you, too.
- Should we wish the STEM guys good luck?
- Good luck!
Good luck, everyone.
It's like hearing our own echo.
Pull us through this.
Will do.
Oh, what's that?
I recognize this.
It's a lockbox for phones.
Oh, a lockbox for phones?
It's a phone jail.
- A phone jail?
- I see.
Does this button unlock it?
- Do we put our phones inside?
- Yes.
Put it inside...
Then, set the timer.
I'll select one hour.
Mine is locked now.
The case doesn't open
even if I press the button.
- Is it really locked?
- Yes, you can't open it now.
I would've gotten better grades
if I had had this back in high school.
Then, I could've gone to SNU...
- I could use it now.
- I'd still make it to SNU.
If I'd had this in my senior year,
I wouldn't have retaken the CSAT.
I had my phone locked away
back when I was studying for the CSAT.
I could've used such a smart product.
GEN-Z'S THROWBACK
You're an oldie.
BORN IN 2007, BORN IN 2003
What do you mean, "oldie"?
But your tone made you sound like one.
I feel pretty nervous today.
- I do, too.
- What with the revenants...
- Team KAIST made it back from hell twice.
- Right.
They had 2 Deathmatches
and 1 redemption round...
Hey, you're right.
They're as seasoned as you can get.
Want to know today's good news?
- That guy who shares your name...
- Yeah?
- Did he look off?
- He looked off today.
I feel amazing today.
- You do?
- My off-phase is over.
- I'm back to my best form.
- That's great.
- No other teams won a second chance.
- I know.
It's all thanks to Jae-han.
- It's a miraculous opportunity for us.
- For sure.
I hope we can avoid the Deathmatches
and play fewer games from now on.
- Hope for the minimum.
- Yes.
If we keep our current trend up,
we'll be shamed as attention seekers.
All teams, please gather
at the main hall for the main match.
Time for a glow-up.
- Here we go.
- To glow-up!
- With a new resolve...
- Exactly.
With a sharper look.
JACKETS FOR THE FINAL 4 TEAMS
Impress everyone with a swish.
Just like this?
Crisp and fine like K-pop idols.
- All right.
- Okay, let's go.
- How about a group photo?
- A group photo?
- Okay.
- Shall we hit every camera?
Hit all corners?
V for victory.
THAT'S IT
FOR THE FINAL 4 CELEBRATION PHOTOS
Everyone looks nice in the jacket.
The vibe's noticeably different.
Our jacket color stands out.
Elite League Season 3.
The surviving teams are as follows.
Team SNU in Medicine,
Team SKKU,
Team SNU in STEM,
and an additional survivor
from the redemption round,
Team KAIST.
Feels like a déjà vu.
Is it a revenge match?
We beat them once. We can do it again.
Exactly.
Only the strong contenders remain now.
From this point on,
you will not team up by divisions.
We will have a competition
between the individual teams.
No more teaming up? That's a shame.
Team SKKU is our rival now.
We have no allies now.
We won't lose, at any rate.
Shoot, my nerves are getting to me.
Today's main match is
Dilemma of the Mean.
- Dilemma?
- Dilemma of the Mean?
- That's a mind game.
- It's a mind game.
In Dilemma of the Mean,
your task is to win points
with a set of three cards.
It is a psychological strategy game.
Each round of Dilemma of the Mean
consists of three mini games.
The first one is the Maximum Match.
Each team will present an equation
with one card undisclosed.
The team with an equation that yields
the largest result wins one point.
If multiple teams have the same maximum,
the point will be awarded to the team
with the second-largest result instead.
- Sounds like a mind game.
- It's a mind game.
It's an epic psychological warfare.
The second mini game is the Minimum Match.
Again, you will present an equation
with one card undisclosed.
The team with an equation that yields
the smallest result wins one point.
If multiple teams have the same minimum,
the point will be awarded to the team
with the second-smallest result instead.
Are negative numbers out?
However,
the smallest result
should be zero or larger.
The third mini game is the Mean Match.
Your target number in this game
is the mean of the winning numbers
from the previous two mini games.
The team that meets the target
wins two points.
In this mini game,
every team shows
all three cards at the same time.
If two teams' results
match the target mean,
they will win one point each.
If more than three teams meet the goal,
we will proceed to the next round
without awarding points.
Oh, man.
If none of the results
meets the target mean,
the team with the closest number
will receive two points.
Sounds interesting.
All teams will receive 41 cards,
each with a number from 0 to 40.
They will also be given three cards
with different arithmetic symbols,
plus, minus, and multiplication.
Please use the cards to make an equation
that has 1 symbol between 2 numbers.
Once used,
the numbered cards cannot be reused.
But you may reuse the symbol cards
in the upcoming rounds.
So numbered ones are discarded after use.
This won't be easy.
We will have six rounds in total.
The two teams with the fewest total points
will compete in the Deathmatch.
If there is a tie,
the team with the larger sum
from the unused cards wins.
All teams,
please start discussing your strategies.
You'll be given 20 minutes.
Okay, I'll get to the bottom of this game.
Let's close the door first.
We should give up the mean.
Here's why.
We get the mean by dividing the sum
of the minimum and the maximum by two.
The former will be close to zero,
so the mean will be
about half of the latter.
Unless we have another times card,
we can't win both the max and the mean.
If the winning equation
from the Maximum Match is 40 times 39,
which yields 1,560,
and the winning equation
from the Minimum Match is 0 times 10,
which yields zero,
the mean value is 780,
the maximum divided in half.
You cannot make an equation
that yields 780
without an extra multiplication card.
In other words,
you would need two multiplication cards
to win both the Maximum Match
and the Mean Match.
I saw the times card
as the most important one
because it decided whether we would win
the Maximum Match or the Mean Match.
If we give up the Mean Match,
we'll be yielding two points to others
every round.
No, no one gets anything
if three teams meet the target.
I think there's a high chance
they'll all go for the Mean Match.
- I've got a superb idea.
- Hit me.
In most mind games,
the players must hide their true goal.
But here, we have to be transparent.
- Right.
- Basically,
it's best to go first
in the Minimum Match.
When we do, we'll flash them
"zero times blank."
It is crucial that you make yourself
crystal clear to your opponents.
We can't exactly talk to each other,
so our two cards
have to send a clear message.
COMBINATIONS THAT MAKE THE STANCE CLEAR
Our cards should say,
"Try us if you want to tank with us."
I think we should reserve
the "zero times blank" option if possible.
If we use that combination,
we can't win that round's Maximum Match.
- That's right.
- Agreed.
We could be forced to give up
the Maximum Match and the Mean Match.
The safest option for us is
to save the times card for the Mean Match.
Suppose we need just one more point
to avoid today's Deathmatch.
- That's when we'll use this combo.
- I get it.
Here's another idea.
Why don't we hold back on the primes?
I like that.
We might need them for the Mean Matches.
For example,
let's say we have to make 115.
YOU NEED 2 PRIMES FOR CERTAIN NUMBERS
Okay, let's try to spare them.
In the earlier rounds, the other teams are
bound to aim high for the Maximum Matches.
- Both STEM teams are bold.
- Yes, they would go for them.
That's for sure.
- Go for huge numbers?
- I can see Team KAIST doing it.
- Team KAIST may try it in Round 1.
- They can just go for it.
Let's say the two STEM teams use
the times card to get a huge number.
That clearly means one of them
will win the Maximum Match.
But then they won't be
able to use the times card
for the Mean Match.
It's rather better for us
if they choose to go bold.
We'll need to save our times card
for the Mean Match of Round 1.
Let's be prudent in Round 1.
The time for strategy meeting is up.
All teams, please gather
at the main hall for the main match.
We need the cards out of their sight,
so keep them behind the platform.
They might see our cards.
I could block their gaze from here.
That may be for the better.
THE COMPETITION IS HEATED
THOUGH THE MATCH HASN'T EVEN BEGUN
Let us begin the main match,
Dilemma of the Mean.
Before we continue,
each team will roll a die twice.
You'll choose the submission order
based on the total,
from the highest to the lowest.
Don't touch this, though.
Not bad.
It's okay.
Team SNU in STEM has the largest total.
We'll go first.
We'll go last.
We'll go third.
INITIAL ORDER:
SNU IN STEM, SNU IN MEDICINE, KAIST, SKKU
THE ORDER WILL ROTATE WITH EACH GAME
Team SNU in STEM will regret
letting us go third.
Well, yes.
But they may have a bright idea
- and done it on purpose.
- True.
Do you want to have our cards set up
to show our confidence?
- That's a strategy, too.
- Yes.
We will now begin Round 1
of Dilemma of the Mean.
Let us begin Maximum Match of Round 1.
Team SNU in STEM,
please submit your equation.
DECLARING THEIR INTENT
WITH THE MULTIPLICATION CARD
I think they went for 40 times 39.
There they go.
They'll probably get the point.
Quick, let's think.
What cards can we throw away?
Let's not get involved.
This is a major make-or-break move.
We can win with our skills.
IF LEFT UNCHALLENGED,
TEAM SNU IN STEM WINS 1 POINT
I'm in tip-top shape today.
Even the die from earlier
- knew today's our day.
- Agreed.
The core idea behind "40 times blank"
was to intimidate the opponents
into using the plus card early on.
This is a bust, anyway.
- I'm sure they used 40 times 39.
- You bet.
Let's use smaller numbers.
- Go for the smallest we can spare.
- Let's do that.
You have 30 seconds left.
Everyone is tucking their tails.
What if their hidden number isn't 39?
We know them. They're no gamblers.
Right? I thought so, too.
Still...
- Okay with these cards?
- Sure.
TEAM SKKU USED THE 2 LARGEST NUMBERS
- Why would they...
- They must think Team SNU in STEM
- used 40 times 38.
- That must be it.
Those guys have the nerve of steel.
Who'd think to try that?
Kudos, guys.
1 MINUTE AGO
But guys...
Are we sure they used 39?
They could've used
something random like 40 times 3.
Want to get involved?
Let's go for it.
The others would've used their plus cards.
Let's use the times card
and meet them head-on.
- Do we go for it?
- Yeah.
You have 30 seconds left.
- It's sink-or-swim now.
- We'll drown with them,
- at least.
- We had to try it.
- I hope they go down together.
- I think they will.
We stand to gain
if they both used 40 times 39.
Let's hope we get the point.
We now have all four equations.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SKKU USED 40 TIMES 39
TO GET THE LARGEST POSSIBLE RESULT
All right. Team SKKU used the times card.
- What?
- Wait, what's going on?
TEAM SNU IN STEM WAS BLUFFING
WITH 40 TIMES 2
- See? They used two.
- We made the right call.
If Team SNU in STEM had used 40 times 39,
they wouldn't have tried to mask 39.
That's why we felt sure
the hidden card couldn't be 39.
By winning the first game
with 40 times 39,
we were able to get ahead
while turning their 40 card into a waste.
It was a sure win for us.
It felt like they used
a random number like two.
DURING STRATEGY MEETING
Let's say
the first team presents "40 times blank."
The others would expect
the blank to be something big.
Then, they would likely save
the times card for the Mean Match
and use the plus card
in the Maximum Match.
Suppose they all chose the plus card.
What's to stop us from using two?
You can't get 80 or larger
with the plus card.
And with a smaller mean,
we get a shot in the Mean Match, too.
I thought it was a clever strategy
because we could then aim for two points.
It'd be funny if anyone used 39.
I'll give it to them, then.
I'll give props to anyone
who saw through us.
How did they manage it?
They're good.
I bet that screwed up their plans.
- That's for sure.
- I know.
I don't think tricks work here.
We shouldn't use them at all.
The winning result
of the Maximum Match in Round 1 is 1,560.
Team SKKU won a point.
Team SKKU can't win the Mean Match now.
No, they're out of the way.
- It's good for us.
- The same goes for Team SNU in STEM.
SYMBOLS CAN'T BE REUSED IN THE SAME ROUND
They used their times card.
This is our dream scenario.
Two teams used large numbers
and the times card,
but we only used small numbers
and the plus card.
We can score with our large numbers.
HOPING TO WIN THE MEAN MATCH
WITH THE MULTIPLICATION CARD
Two teams used the times card,
so we can win the Mean Match for sure.
- Let's go get it.
- All right.
Let us begin the Minimum Match of Round 1.
Team SNU in Medicine...
Team KAIST...
Team SKKU...
MINIMUM MATCH OF ROUND 1
I guess we can decide which team wins now.
Which team wins a point
is now up to Team SNU in STEM.
We should've tried to get
in Team SNU in STEM's good books.
We should back Team KAIST.
Team SKKU and Team SNU in Medicine
might be hoping
to reach the finals together.
EQUATION SUBMITTED
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 1, TEAM KAIST: 2
TEAM SKKU ALSO HAS 1,
SAME AS TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S EQUATION ALSO YIELDS 1
Hey, they got us.
They're out to get us.
- They want us to go down?
- Why?
AS THE SOLE TEAM WITH 2,
TEAM KAIST WINS THE POINT
This is dope.
The winning result
of the Minimum Match in Round 1 is 2.
Team KAIST won a point.
The two teams with the times card
will win the Mean Match, right?
- Yes, they'll get a point each.
- With a point each?
The target mean in Round 1 is 781.
MAXIMUM: 1,560, MINIMUM: 2
MEAN: 781
- Our goal is 781...
- So we go for 782.
We can't get 781. We need 71 for that.
- So, 782...
- That's it.
Or we can go for 780
and use the equation we prepared.
Can we make an equation that yields 782?
That's 17 times 23 times 2.
We can get it with 34 times 23.
NO MASKED CARDS THIS TIME
All teams, please submit your equations.
ROUND 1 TARGET MEAN: 781
+1 DIFFERENCE, -1 DIFFERENCE
Team SNU in Medicine and Team KAIST
won a point each.
- Team KAIST won 2 points this round.
- Yes, they won 2 games.
We can't just let them take the lead.
Of course not.
Let us begin the Maximum Match of Round 2.
- We don't need to gamble at all.
- Let's be conventional.
TEAM KAIST USES THE TWO LARGEST NUMBERS
We presented a set of surefire cards
whenever we went first
so we could win points.
Dang, they'll win another point.
Team KAIST must've used the times card.
It makes no sense otherwise.
They barely made it back
through the redemption round.
They wouldn't have thrown away
40 and 39 in a gamble.
- Especially when they have two points.
- That too.
Team KAIST already has two points.
- They have no reason to gamble.
- Right.
- Let's toss this game.
- They must've used the times card.
We're using the plus card no matter what.
USES THE PLUS SYMBOL
WITH DISPOSABLE NUMBERS
Let's throw in two useless cards
with the plus card now
and win the Mean Match.
That's upside down.
They put the secret card upside down.
We now have all four equations.
We'll probably win.
- I bet they all used the plus card.
- Agreed.
- What idiot would've used the times card?
- No one would've done that.
The winning result is 1,560.
Team KAIST won a point.
We'll win if we don't slip up.
HAS A 3-POINT LEAD
- Fingers crossed.
- We'll place second at least.
There's no guarantee
we can win the Mean Match.
Three teams have the times card.
NO POINTS IN A 3-WAY TIE
We have more to gain
if they all fight to get the mean.
There's a high chance no one will win.
- It's better for us.
- Sure.
If they all meet the target...
Let us begin the Minimum Match of Round 2.
- Team SNU in STEM has no points.
- Yeah.
- They'll use zero, then.
- They have to.
In case they don't go for 0,
let's make an equation that yields 1.
So they're going with one?
Wait, we can use zero this time.
We can't win two points with the mean.
I second Jong-yun's idea.
If we save the times card,
then three teams will go
into the Mean Match with it.
We're likely to get a tie, then.
TEAM SNU IN STEM
DECIDES TO WIN 1 SURE POINT
They used the zero.
They're getting a zero, right?
- Isn't it better for us?
- It doesn't matter.
- We and Team SKKU can win a point each.
- Of course.
Let them take a point.
We can win one later.
MINIMUM MATCH OF ROUND 2
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
- We good?
- Team SNU in STEM will win anyway.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
The winning result
of the Minimum Match in Round 2 is zero.
Team SNU in STEM won a point.
The target mean in Round 2 is 780.
Let's now win the guaranteed one point.
- We've got to get 780 now.
- What, 780?
We need 26 and 30.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE AND TEAM SKKU
MET THE TARGET MEAN
Team SKKU used the same cards.
- They did?
- Yeah.
What we need to keep in mind now
is that if the maximum is 1560
and the minimum is 0 in any future round,
we can't meet the target mean.
The two possible combinations for 780
are 20 times 29
or 26 times 30.
As Team SKKU already used 26, 30, and 39,
they can't make an equation
that yields 780.
Isn't it the same for all others?
Not for Team SNU in STEM.
They still have 39.
We each took on a team
to check the cards they used.
I'll check Team SNU in Medicine.
I'll take on Team KAIST.
TEAM SNU IN STEM AS WELL
I'll handle Team KAIST.
Why don't you monitor the general trends?
Keep them in mind.
Let's take on a team each, Seung-hyeon.
Memorize the used cards, okay?
ALL FOUR TEAMS ARE TRACKING
EVERYONE ELSE'S REMAINING CARDS
Let us begin the Maximum Match of Round 3.
Why don't we mask a number?
We tried bluffing once.
I don't think it will work now.
Let's think of a way
to win the Mean Match instead.
I don't think it will hurt
to try our luck once more.
Team SNU in Medicine still has 39 and 40.
They can win the Maximum Match
in any other round.
- So they might not use them now?
- That's my point.
If our gamble fails again,
we'll lose another point
that we could've easily won.
That's true.
I don't know,
but I still think we should risk it.
- I agree with Myeong-su.
- Let's gamble.
To go up to the second place,
I thought we needed to take risks
by throwing curveballs
instead of sticking
with tried-and-true methods.
Come on, let's reach a decision.
What do you say?
We're gamblers, all right.
TEAM SNU IN STEM DECIDES
TO TAKE ON ANOTHER GAMBLE
We thought that one successful bluffing
would help us overtake the others.
The masked number has to be a large one.
That's likely a large number.
Then, Team SNU in Medicine
will counter with 40 times 39.
- How so?
- Otherwise, Team SNU in STEM wins.
Oh, they used the times card.
Their best set is 39 times 38.
Team SNU in Medicine
will go for 39 times 40.
- They have no reason not to, right?
- Exactly.
Team SNU in STEM used 39.
They might've used 39 times 38, right?
What? They didn't use 40.
What's going on?
Still, 40 times 38 is bigger.
- Oh, so that's bigger.
- What a smart move.
- They're good.
- How clever.
They managed to keep 39.
Can't we still beat them with 40 times 38?
- Well, yes.
- Then we can use 39 in the next turn.
The others have 37 and 38 at most.
Let's fool them with 39 plus 37.
- The hidden card has to be 40.
- For sure.
Their faces fell,
so it must have been a bluff.
- They could've used 39 times 3.
- Yes, something small.
We'll secure one point at a time.
- Do we just discard some?
- Of course.
TEAM KAIST LETS GO OF UNNECESSARY CARDS
TEAM SKKU DOES THE SAME
We now have all four equations.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S BLUFF FAILED AGAIN
- They made sure to win that point.
- That's safer.
If you're angling to win a point,
you'd better make sure you get it.
Why did Team SNU in STEM do that?
I wonder why they keep bluffing that way.
They wasted a useful card
with 40 times 2 earlier.
Guess they didn't learn from it.
We ended up giving everyone a lesson
that gambling only leads to ruin.
We'll need to focus on moves
and countermoves from now on.
The winning result
of the Maximum Match in Round 3 is 1,520.
Team SNU in Medicine won a point.
Let us begin the Minimum Match of Round 3.
What do you want us to go with?
It's either 1 or 2.
- Right.
- Wait, quick.
THEY MASK A NUMBER
TO HIDE WHETHER THE RESULT IS 1 OR 2
Our result will be two.
Do we let them know?
- It'd be better to hide it.
- Do as he says.
But why hide it?
Transparency would tempt them
to go for one.
That makes sense.
- No masking this time.
- Here's the minus card.
Here we go.
TEAM KAIST DISCLOSES ALL THEIR NUMBERS
Then, we must target one, no?
- Yes, we shouldn't take a loss.
- Let's avoid a loss.
What's Team SNU in STEM's choice?
Team SNU in STEM wouldn't mind
Team KAIST winning
because they're in the lead.
Team SNU in STEM's current target
is the team in third place.
They can't have Team SKKU win.
They'd much rather let Team KAIST win.
- They would let Team KAIST win.
- It's the right choice.
- Why bother masking?
- Yeah, why?
- We're dying to know.
- Why, though?
I'm so curious.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SKKU: 1, TEAM KAIST: 2
Oh, they went for one.
TEAM SNU IN STEM: 1
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 2
NO POINTS THIS TIME
Great.
- That's the logical choice.
- Totally.
No team won a point.
WHEN THERE IS NO WINNER,
THE MINIMUM IS THE MEAN OF ALL 4 VALUES
The target mean in Round 3 is 760.75.
No one will try to hold us back
once we become untouchable.
- We should overpower them.
- They'll go for each other's throats.
Let's win points as fast as we can.
We should use 38 times 20.
Is it necessary?
But 38...
TEAM SKKU AIMS TO WIN A POINT
WITH 38 TIMES 20
We should use the smaller numbers first.
Save the cards
that will give us a larger sum.
Team SKKU hasn't used
many single-digit numbers.
There's a chance they're trying to keep
five consecutive numbers like us.
In Dilemma of the Mean,
there is one additional rule.
After all six rounds are completed,
teams with five consecutive numbers
remaining in their possession
will be given one additional point.
In a tie,
the team with a larger total wins.
- We can beat them with 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8.
- Okay.
DECIDES TO KEEP 4, 5, 6, 7, AND 8
FOR A LARGER TOTAL
All teams, please submit your equations.
TEAM SKKU AND TEAM KAIST
MET THE TARGET MEAN OF 760.75
MEAN MATCH IN ROUND 3
TEAM KAIST: 4, TEAM SKKU: 3
Let us begin the Maximum Match of Round 4.
What matters in the later rounds
is which team has better cards left.
We used cards in a random fashion.
We threw away many useless cards,
so we still have decent cards left.
To narrow down the 2-point gap,
we must win 2 points in 1 round twice.
- Don't give up yet. Let's keep going.
- Okay.
Team KAIST, please submit your equation.
Okay, we're going first
in the Maximum Match, right?
We can't win this game anyway
because of Team SNU in Medicine.
They still have 39.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE HAS 39
- Give it up.
- We can discard a few.
Turn it around.
Which cards do we use?
Do we make a play for this game?
They wouldn't have wasted the times card.
Right, I'm sure that's the plus card.
Does either of Team SNUs still have 39?
Team SNU in STEM doesn't.
How about 38?
- Let me think. They have it.
- They do?
We can't use the times card anyway.
Shall we ditch a few cards?
- With the plus card, yes.
- All right.
- Make our sum bigger than Team KAIST's.
- Then...
I bet they both used the plus card.
Otherwise, they would've warned us
- with large numbers.
- Every single point matters to them.
I think they'll try to win
the Mean Match, too.
Since that's the case,
we don't have to go all-in here.
Let's use 32 and 23
and leave the symbol masked.
We've got to be bold.
Bold how?
With the times card?
Yes, go big or go home.
You have ten seconds left.
Things aren't going well
for Team SNU in STEM.
They must've used the times card.
They're desperate to win points.
It could really be the times card.
Looks like the times card.
Using the times card here
means they gave up the Mean Match.
All we need to do is win a point
every round using the times card.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SKKU, TEAM KAIST
Oh, come on.
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S EQUATION
HAS A PLUS CARD AND YIELDS 71
There we go.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE USED THE PLUS CARD
I think there will come a time
when we need to win
the Maximum Match with the plus card
- and the Mean Match with the times card.
- Agreed.
We'll need that at least once...
- To secure a lead?
- Exactly.
I think we can take this game
with the plus card.
Team SKKU and Team SNU in STEM
could've both used the plus card.
Let's go with the plus card.
- Which cards do we use?
- Big numbers.
All right.
WON A POINT WITH THE PLUS CARD
The winning result
of the Maximum Match in Round 4 is 72.
Team SNU in Medicine won a point.
ROUND 4
MINIMUM MATCH
Which team still has the zero card?
Team SNU in STEM doesn't.
What about the other two?
- Team KAIST has zero.
- Really?
- Same with Team SNU in Medicine.
- Oh, yeah?
Then, let's use it ahead of them.
We only have a couple of rounds left.
Let's use "zero times blank" now.
If everyone uses that pair,
we all go down together.
Team KAIST will use the Turn Update card.
TEAM KAIST USES THE TURN UPDATE CARD
In Dilemma of the Mean,
there are two special items.
The first item is the Turn Update card.
If this card, you can select
when to submit your equation.
The second item is the Reveal Only 1 card.
You can use this to mask
two cards of your equation.
Among these two special items,
each team can only use one
throughout the game.
Team KAIST will use the Turn Update card.
We knew the fight for the Mean Match
would be intense.
So rather than taking part in that,
we wanted to claim a sure-win point
and prevent Team SKKU
from winning a point.
TEAM SKKU WAS TO GO FIRST
That means they're using
"zero times blank" now.
That complicates things for us.
They predicted our move.
I can't believe this.
What do we do now?
Team KAIST used the Turn Update card.
Which turn would you like to take?
We'd like to go first.
- For the "zero times blank."
- You bet.
Great.
Our target mean will be 36 now.
- We're in big trouble.
- Yeah, really.
We can't meet the target mean.
To reach 36,
we needed 4 times 9 or 3 times 12.
But my team had already used 12.
And if we had chosen to use 4 and 9,
we would've had to give up
our chain of five consecutive cards.
Team SKKU already used 9 and 18.
They can't meet the target mean, right?
What about 3 times 12?
You're right.
They can use them because they have both.
But the moment they do,
- their five consecutive numbers are gone.
- That breaks their chain.
That in itself is a victory for us.
If they have to use the minus card...
SEO-YEON HAS BEEN MONITORING TEAM SKKU
They need to use 37 minus 1
or 3 times 12.
Either way, they lose their chain.
Team SKKU, please submit your equation.
Don't we have to get 36 in the Mean Match?
We can use 12 times 3,
but that will break our number chain.
Do we keep the number chain or not?
Let's review the remaining cards.
We've got to do it now.
Let's stay calm and lay them all out.
We already used 26.
We still have 30 and 31.
To keep our chain,
we have to give up the Mean Match.
I say we give up the chain
and use 12 times 3.
If we had given up the Mean Match,
some other team could've won two points.
So I thought it was wiser
not to give them the edge.
Let's use smaller numbers
in case we get tied.
Smaller numbers are better.
GIVES UP ON THE CHAIN TO USE 5 AND 6
- Pick the useless ones.
- We've got to.
OPTS TO WIN 1 POINT LATER WITH THE CHAIN
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
MINIMUM MATCH IN ROUND 4
TEAM KAIST: 5
We made the logical choice.
- All right. We killed it.
- The timing was crazy.
The target mean in Round 4 is 36.
We lose if we miss
the golden opportunity to score.
Why not go for it when we can?
About Team KAIST.
Can they subtract a small number
from a big number to get 36?
Something like 37 minus 1.
If they can, we can skip this.
- Something like 37 minus 1?
- Can they do it?
No, they can't.
They used up from 0 to 12.
- Really?
- You have ten seconds left.
What a shame. If they can take this game,
we don't have to bother.
All teams, please submit your equations.
TEAM SNU IN STEM, TEAM SKKU
Team SKKU and Team SNU in STEM
won a point each.
Let us begin the Maximum Match of Round 5.
- We only have two rounds left, right?
- Yes.
Let's make sure we score
in the Maximum Match.
And in the Minimum Match with the zero.
We still have our number chain.
If we and Team SKKU keep obtaining
a point each, we win.
- Right?
- Absolutely.
We have no reason to take risks.
That's true.
We should look carefree.
If we take too long,
they'll think we've overthought it.
Let's make it look
like we're using the times card.
Yeah, this is necessary
to win more than two points.
- Is this right?
- Yes, we ran the numbers.
They used 37 and 38.
We've got to use the times card
in the Minimum Match this round.
We should use the minus card now.
- Let's use the minus card now.
- Why?
I feel like we might need the plus card
in the Mean Match.
Team SKKU, please submit your equation.
This is our best bet.
We can't win without it.
We now have all four equations.
All teams, please reveal the secret card.
- The minus card?
- The minus card.
Everything depends on their symbol.
TEAM KAIST: 1
TEAM SNU IN STEM: 75
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 29
TEAM SNU IN STEM IS LIKELY TO WIN
We're good
as long as Team SKKU doesn't win.
They wouldn't have used
the times card, right?
- That's too risky even for them.
- Let's see.
...the secret card.
We can take our time.
TEAM SKKU USED THE MULTIPLICATION CARD
TEAM SKKU'S UNEXPECTED VICTORY
Team SKKU got that point.
Team SNU in Medicine seems to be
trying to keep a chain.
Why don't we take advantage of that?
Because I was monitoring the cards
used by Team SNU in Medicine,
I could see that they were keeping
numbers near ten for a chain.
We can use 12 times 3,
but that will break our number chain.
TEAM SKKU GAVE UP ON THEIR NUMBER CHAIN
IF THEY GET A TIE, TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
WILL WIN FROM THEIR BONUS POINT
Let's make an equation
with a bigger result than theirs.
We saw Team SNU in Medicine
as our main rival for survival.
TO SECURE 1 POINT,
TEAM SKKU USED THE MULTIPLICATION CARD
Team SKKU must've gone with that
because they could get 56, no?
You bet.
Their equation looks too calculated.
They definitely planned it.
Can Team SNU in Medicine get 56?
- Team SNU in Medicine can't get 56.
- They can't?
- For real? Did you check all the numbers?
- Yeah.
- We have the next game in the bag.
- Of course, we can't lose.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE CAN'T MEET 56
WITH THEIR REMAINING CARDS
Out of all the cases
where you could get 56 with the plus card,
none were in our arsenal.
Team SKKU can get 56 with 27 plus 29.
Let us begin the Minimum Match of Round 5.
Team SNU in Medicine,
please submit your equation.
- We can't help it. This is all we have.
- It's our only option.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
TRIES TO SECURE 1 POINT WITH 0
The winning result
of the Minimum Match in Round 5 is zero.
Team SNU in Medicine won a point.
The target mean in Round 5 is 56.
Can Team SNU in STEM
get 56 with the times card?
With the times card?
We need both teams to get it
so each would win only one point.
- Team SKKU has 27 and 29--
- We're screwed if either wins 2 points.
Do they have 7 and 8?
- Do they?
- Give me a minute.
IF TEAM SKKU WINS 2 POINTS,
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE WILL LOSE
Can Team SNU in STEM meet the goal?
- They can. They still have 27 and 29.
- Really?
Won't this work?
Your time is up.
All teams, please submit your equations.
ROUND 5 TARGET MEAN: 56
For now...
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 57
What's up with them?
TEAM SNU IN STEM FAILS TO MEET THE TARGET
I thought they had the cards.
All teams, please submit your equations.
- What's with them?
- Why 6 times 8?
That's just 48.
- Oh, they used the plus card already.
- Oh, right!
TEAM SKKU WINS 2 POINTS
IF TEAM KAIST FAILS TO MEET THE TARGET
TEAM KAIST: 56
They did it.
- Hey, Team KAIST did it.
- Right, they have 56.
- We're good now.
- They used the minus card.
TEAM KAIST AND TEAM SKKU WINS 1 POINT EACH
- If Team KAIST won...
- We're good.
It's all good now.
There we go.
THANKS TO TEAM SNU IN STEM'S FAILURE,
TEAM KAIST AND TEAM SKKU WON A POINT
Thank goodness.
The mind game with Team SKKU...
We can beat them. We have our chain.
That's true.
We're really close to survival now.
We're almost there. Let's keep it up.
Team SKKU and Team KAIST won a point each.
We don't have to worry
about elimination now.
We can win the Minimum Match
with our "zero times blank."
I'll use the Turn Update card
the moment the next round begins.
Let us begin the Maximum Match of Round 6.
Team SKKU would like
to use the Turn Update card.
Which turn would you like to take?
We would like to go last.
TO GO FIRST IN THE MINIMUM MATCH
So they want to end it all
with the Minimum Match.
Team KAIST,
Team SNU in STEM,
Team SNU in Medicine,
and Team SKKU.
That is the order of submission
in the next game.
It's time we decided on our opponent
for the Deathmatch.
Yeah, we can't get an upset win now.
The gap is too big.
So do we go with Team SNU in Medicine?
We can't exactly make Team KAIST
drop to the bottom, can we?
There's no way
we can take Team KAIST down now.
We should smash Team SNU in Medicine.
I think Team SNU in Medicine
is the right choice.
I was ready to take them down.
Do we go out swinging now?
Team SNU in STEM...
We'd like to use a special item.
The Reveal 1 Number?
- No, the Reveal Only 1 card.
- Reveal Only 1.
Team SNU in STEM used
the Reveal Only 1 card.
You can reveal only one card
when you submit your equation.
Team KAIST, please submit your equation.
- This is our best set.
- Understood.
TEAM KAIST USES THEIR MINUS CARD
IN THE MAXIMUM MATCH
- That means they've given up this game.
- Of course.
What do we do?
- Which cards do we mask?
- Everything except the times card.
Showing only the times card ensures
that we win the Maximum Match.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
- Which large numbers do they have?
- I don't think it matters...
Yes, I'm sure of it.
Now that the times card is out,
Team SNU in Medicine can't win
the two remaining games now.
Team SNU in STEM used the times card.
They used the times card.
That means we have to use it, too.
They're forcing our hand.
- Yeah, we've got to use it now.
- Right.
This is it. There's no other way for us.
We can't risk a defeat.
- Our worst-case scenario is a tie.
- Right, if they win two points--
The absolute worst case is a tie.
Since the total of the remaining cards
works as a tiebreaker,
- I'd like to use smaller numbers first.
- Good call.
- I have them lined up here--
- We can use four, no?
- Sure.
- In that case...
TEAM SKKU CHOOSES TO DISCARD
SMALLER NUMBERS
Please reveal the secret card.
TEAM SKKU, TEAM KAIST
TEAM SNU IN STEM USED
THE MULTIPLICATION CARD
It's smaller than ours.
Team SNU in Medicine won a point.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 6
Let us begin the Minimum Match of Round 6.
TEAM SKKU GOES FIRST
THANKS TO THE TURN UPDATE CARD
The winning result
of the Minimum Match in Round 6 is zero.
We have a one-point lead on Team KAIST.
TEAM SKKU: 7
The Mean Match will be a watershed point.
The target mean in Round 6 is 487.5.
All teams, please submit your equations.
ROUND 6 TARGET MEAN: 487.5
Check with Team KAIST.
IF YOU DON'T MIND ME ASKING...
CAN YOU MEET THE TARGET?
YES!
They have it.
- They've got it.
- Really?
TEAM KAIST WINS
- What's with that freaky equation?
- Their result is so close to the target.
- They won 2 points.
- They got 483.
None of them can score.
They all used the times card.
Do we use these from the number chain?
We had been holding on
to our number chain,
but we noticed that we could win
the Mean Match at the end.
So we decided to give up the number chain
and win two points in the Mean Match.
Team KAIST won two points.
TEAM KAIST SECURES FIRST PLACE
IN DILEMMA OF THE MEAN
We just made our way
from the redemption round.
It was inspiring that we placed first
right after our return.
I felt like we proved our skills.
- Props to Team KAIST.
- They're so good.
They almost got eliminated twice
but came on top this time.
- So good.
- They're scary.
They're amazing.
That concludes Round 6
of Dilemma of the Mean.
If you have a set of consecutive numbers,
please present the set.
"No team qualified."
I think all three teams have them.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
CHECKS THE REMAINING CARDS
They have 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11.
We'd have won
if we had been playing poker.
Team SNU in STEM and Team SNU in Medicine
won a bonus point.
Now, the tiebreaker
will be the total of the remaining cards.
Team SKKU would have big numbers.
But they look so down.
Do they have small numbers?
- I doubt it.
- We'd have to go against them.
Come on, they're pretty strategic guys.
Team SNU in Medicine
and Team SKKU are currently tied.
Based on the total
of the remaining cards...
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S
REMAINING CARDS: 7, 8, 9, 10, AND 11
TEAM SKKU'S TOTAL OF REMAINING CARDS
MUST BE OVER 45 TO WIN
Based on the total
of the remaining cards...
Team SKKU takes the higher rank.
TEAM SKKU'S REMAINING CARDS
28, 34, 35, 36, AND 37
The lowest-ranking two teams,
Team SNU in Medicine and Team SNU in STEM,
please prepare for the Deathmatch.
We've got this.
I'm so relieved.
My gosh.
Would you look at that?
That match-up is fire.
We're seeing the infighting of Team SNUs.
Which team will prove themselves
as the true Team SNU?
- This should be worth watching.
- Of course.
Which team do you think will win?
My money is on Team SNU in Medicine.
- That's the general vibe.
- Yes.
Based on the general vibe
and how today's game went...
- I'm going to root for Team SNU in STEM.
- Same.
We'll finally be able to gauge
each med student's strengths.
Let's pull through this Deathmatch.
We've got this.
The lowest-ranking two teams,
Team SNU in Medicine and Team SNU in STEM,
please prepare for the Deathmatch.
We can win this. Let's do our best.
Let's focus.
We can beat anyone when we're in the zone.
Surviving two teams,
please go to your base camps.
I was hoping to see
a match-up between the two Team SNUs.
We'll be the ones advancing,
not Team SNU in STEM.
Look at those menacing forearms.
PRETTY INTIMIDATING
We had a Deathmatch anyway.
Why not stake the title of Team SNU?
Our pride was at risk.
I was determined to win at all costs.
My money is on Team SNU in STEM.
I think they're going to win.
Team SNU in STEM
has a star-studded roster.
These 3 ranked
in the top 4 of STEM Division.
Team SNU in STEM
might have the upper hand.
- Still...
- But then again...
Team SNU in Medicine
isn't exactly outmatched.
- Seo-yeon...
- She placed third.
- Seung-hyeon placed fourth.
- Seung-hyeon...
Today's Deathmatch is
Block Connect Five.
- Finally.
- We've been waiting for this.
We needed that.
Connect Five.
I like it.
Connect Five with blocks?
In Block Connect Five,
you will be given 3D pieces.
The first to form a block of five cells
wins the game.
It's three-dimensional.
It's three-dimensional Connect Five.
Oh, shoot. That looks like so much fun.
The game will be played on a 5-by-5 board.
Each player will be given five pieces
in either black or white.
Among the five pieces,
one immovable piece will be in place
before the game begins.
When the game begins,
1-MINUTE DEADLINE
you will take turns to place a piece.
There are two ways
to place a piece on the board.
First,
you can place a piece
so that its three-cell side
meets the board.
Second,
you can place your piece
on top of a piece already on the board.
Please remember that the one-cell side
must meet the board.
They can't use the two-cell side.
- This is out of the option.
- That's right.
To place your piece above another one,
you need to find a perch
to fit in the reverse L shape.
Additionally, you cannot place your piece
in the highlighted area
until your second turn.
From the point where all five pieces
of both players are on the board,
you may start moving your pieces.
However, if your opponent's piece
is resting on top of yours,
you cannot move it.
A stack like this
can limit your opponent's movement
while securing two cells.
Yes, you claim two cells.
It's no good to have it at the bottom.
In the bird's-eye view,
the player who successfully connects
five cells in their color wins.
- The bird's-eye view is the guide.
- From the top?
- It's going to be so confusing.
- I know.
Wow, that's way too advanced.
This tests your spatial awareness.
Not just spatial awareness, though.
Your strategic thinking, too.
There will be five rounds in total.
Each round will be played
on a one-on-one basis.
Rounds 1 to 4 require different players,
but anyone can participate in Round 5.
Everyone has to participate.
All four of us must compete.
How stressful.
Everyone gets to fight once,
and then the clash of Ace players.
Let's not play all five rounds.
- Let's end it in three rounds.
- All right.
- We'll be able to find the winning moves.
- I think so, too.
- Is there something like a double-three?
- That's what I also wonder.
As Team SNU in Medicine
won more points in the main match,
they will decide
which team goes first in Round 1.
Both teams,
please start discussing your strategies.
You'll be given 20 minutes.
Team SNU in STEM has that tactician
in the top 0.6% in chess.
Let's say Gang-hyeon gets a win.
But he won't get another shot
if the other three med guys win.
What if he teaches the strategy
to his teammates?
That could work.
- He could spoon-feed them.
- Right.
SPOON-FEEDING NOW
The first player has to do this.
We're working with the premise
that the first player does this.
There's no way they wouldn't.
The center is way too valuable.
Since we can get
a diagonal five-cell block...
We assumed that the first player
would claim the center cell first.
When we're going first...
TARGETING THE CENTER
SAME AS TEAM SNU IN STEM
It's because if we have the center,
we have four options to spread out.
One, two, three, and four.
If we claim a corner,
we only have three options.
It's clear that we must claim the center
when we're going first.
I think we should try to layer more.
They become immovable.
The opponent can't move their own piece.
Laying a piece flat on the board
is disadvantageous--
We're virtually giving them a chance
to place their piece above it.
It's better to layer our piece
above another
because the opponent can't move it.
You can't cover up the second layer.
Place a piece flat,
and we gain three cells.
But place it upright,
and we gain two cells
while eliminating a cell for them.
We can move our piece around,
whereas they're stuck.
Exactly. We can hold them down.
But placing our piece on top of theirs
might not always be good.
What if we remove a piece
and end up completing
a five-cell block for them?
YOUR OPPONENT WINS
We have to know what's underneath
before we decide to move a piece.
Once you grab a piece,
there's no going back.
Think carefully in advance
because the first layer is invisible.
It's pretty confusing
when you look at the board this way.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE PLAYS TRIAL GAMES
I think this is a pretty good move.
ALL PIECES HAVE BEEN PLACED
We can now move them, right?
What can I move now? Nothing much.
Just these three, right?
There's this term
called zugzwang in chess.
So basically,
it's a situation
where all your pieces are engaged.
No pieces are free to move,
so you end up making a bad move.
I think we might see a similar moment
in Block Connect Five.
What's the setup
that will guarantee me a win?
- That's what I'm trying to find.
- We need it.
Like the double-three--
Yes, something
like the double-three in Connect Five...
- We need to find that ultimate move.
- Exactly.
We'll probably go second
in Rounds 1 and 3.
It's as good as fixed.
- Gang-hyeon and I can take on one each.
- We could do that.
I'm feeling pretty good.
- Let's do as you say.
- Okay.
It's all about not slipping up.
Take time to think it through.
I trust you.
Let me have at it.
ROUND 1: KIM DONG-GEON
ROUND 2: SONG MYEONG-SU
ROUND 3: KIM GANG-HYEON
ROUND 4: HAN JONG-YUN
ROUND 1: JOO MIN-SEO
ROUND 2: LEE SEUNG-HYEON
ROUND 3: HAN SEO-YEON
ROUND 4: KIM MIN-SEOK
The time for strategy meeting is up.
Both teams, please gather
at the main hall for the Deathmatch.
- SNU!
- For independence!
- Let's go, SNU!
We've got this.
They'll probably feel uneasy
because we get to go first in Round 1.
Let's relax.
Why do I feel like we're going to win?
You feel like we're going to win?
Well, I'd say that's just normal
because we're obviously going to win.
FIRST-EVER TEAM SNU SHOWDOWN
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE VS TEAM SNU IN STEM
We'll now begin Round 1
of the Deathmatch, Block Connect Five.
Which team will win
the battle of Team SNUs?
All four members have to battle it out.
We'll see what everyone is made of.
It will decide which is the true Team SNU.
Players competing in Round 1
are Team SNU in Medicine's Joo Min-seo
and Team SNU in STEM's Kim Dong-geon.
One of them has to bear the dishonor
of being the first Team SNU
to be eliminated.
That sounds so crazy.
What's more, they come in fourth.
This decides fourth place?
This is way too intense.
As Team SNU in Medicine
held a higher rank in the main match,
their player will decide who goes first.
We'll go first.
Are you sure about this?
Of course.
I was sure I could beat the disadvantage.
I felt confident going in.
First player, please place a piece.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S TURN
She has to go for the center.
That's a shocker.
AGAINST ALL EXPECTATION,
JOO MIN-SEO DIDN'T CLAIM THE CENTER
My team concluded that the first player
had to take the center at the outset.
So Min-seo's first move was unexpected.
It threw me off,
but I still thought it was important
to take the center.
JOO MIN-SEO HAS A 4-CELL BLOCK
Hey, she won.
What the heck?
It's basically over, isn't it?
What?
- She won.
- We won.
He didn't come prepared.
DURING STRATEGY MEETING
What's the setup
that will guarantee me a win?
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE FOCUSED
ON FINDING ULTIMATE MOVES
Because we'd be going first in Round 1...
We tried to find ways
for the first player to secure victory.
While searching for the moves
that would allow us to win...
Hey, the game's over.
- We start from here, right?
- Yes.
Let's say...
We place it like this.
We learned that it was critical
to claim the 4-by-4 point.
Let's say we took it on our first move.
If the opponent didn't defend properly,
we could complete our five-cell block
with the pieces in the second layer.
Even if the opponent places a piece
in the first layer as a defense,
you can place your piece over it
to complete a five-cell block.
If they don't,
you can place your piece on the board
to get a five-cell block.
We now have one way to secure a win.
We can win with this.
AS PLANNED,
JOO MIN-SEO CLAIMS THE 4-BY-4 POINT
THE RED POINT MUST BE DEFENDED
BUT KIM DONG-GEON DIDN'T GRASP
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S STRATEGY
Shoot, I missed that.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S 5-CELL BLOCK
It must've been
a huge surprise to Dong-geon.
Our plan worked. He didn't see it coming.
I realized that Team SNU in Medicine
came well-prepared.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 1,
TEAM SNU IN STEM: 0
Kudos to your hard work.
I can't believe I missed that.
- That was a finisher.
- I know.
We can win when we go first.
What do I do?
- What?
- What should I lead with?
We have our strategy.
You can follow the plan.
That was the fastest defeat on record.
Dong-geon lost...
- I can't believe it.
- Me neither.
- That was a given.
- It was perfect.
Simply perfect, just as we planned.
- Good luck.
- Great job.
We know our strategy best,
so they can't use it against us.
Of course. We've got this.
How do we counter that strategy?
With good defense.
Good. We won the first round.
Yes, I bet their morale is crushed.
Looks like Seung-hyeon is up next.
It's okay.
Let's do our thing, okay?
BLOCK CONNECT FIVE
ROUND 2
ROUND 2 PLAYER OF TEAM SNU IN STEM
SONG MYEONG-SU
- You've got this. Get us the win.
- Good luck.
ROUND 2 PLAYER OF TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE
LEE SEUNG-HYEON
I saw Seung-hyeon as the best tactician
of Team SNU in Medicine.
I thought defeating him
would turn the tide in my team's favor.
As Team SNU in STEM lost Round 1,
their player will decide who goes first.
TEAM SNU IN STEM
I'll go first.
Please place your piece.
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S TURN
How would Seung-hyeon react
if Myeong-su used their previous tactic?
Would he go for a new hack
or nab the center cell?
I did consider
using the opponent's strategy
because it was incredible.
BEFORE ROUND 2
Should I copy their plan?
- From just now?
- Yes.
But that's a tool
they know better than we do.
But it seemed too risky to try
a strategy that I didn't know well.
So I went with our original plan.
CLAIMS THE CENTER AS PLANNED
Nice and easy.
I don't think we can call it a bad choice.
You have 30 seconds left.
Guys.
How do you defend against this?
- You get a double-three.
- You can't counter that.
If Myeong-su places his piece
like the graphic on screen,
he can get a double-three in his color.
Regardless of what Seung-hyeon does next,
Myeong-su can get a five-cell block
no matter what.
SONG MYEONG-SU PLACES HIS PIECE ELSEWHERE
I was so relieved
to have narrowly escaped the danger.
- That would've ended it.
- Sure.
It's a pity Myeong-su didn't see this.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S 4-CELL BLOCK
DEFENDS SUCCESSFULLY
ATTACKS WITH ANOTHER 4-CELL BLOCK
Myeong-su should put a piece
on top of his own, no?
Sure.
That puts Myeong-su at a disadvantage.
He lost the edge of going first.
All right, good job.
Defense and offense at the same time.
Good call.
Seung-hyeon has to find a way
to counter it.
There we go.
All pieces have been placed.
Song Myeong-su, please move a piece.
Leaving the center open?
He can't do much, can he?
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S 4-CELL BLOCK
Both of them are running a tight ship.
They'll have to wait
for the other to mess up.
BOTH DEFEND WITHOUT A MISTAKE
You have 30 seconds left.
This is frustrating.
I don't see
any offense options for Myeong-su.
Song Myeong-su will now take his turn.
Lee Seung-hyeon will now take his turn.
I was forced to be on defense,
so I kept thinking about ways
to turn the tables.
Isn't that cell indefensible?
You can't place one here.
Lee Seung-hyeon just built
a four-cell block.
As a piece cannot be placed
on its one-cell side without a perch,
Myeong-su cannot place
a new piece in the highlighted spot.
He can't do anything
about that lower right corner.
Since I couldn't see
a suitable move for defense...
- An attack with a four-cell block.
- So that's his next move.
- That calls for defense.
- Of course.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S 5-CELL BLOCK
Oh, I didn't realize
he could cap it off with that piece.
That never occurred to me.
It's 2 to 0 now.
That was fire.
- Props to him.
- That never crossed my mind.
Team SNU in Medicine's Lee Seung-hyeon
won Round 2 of Block Connect Five.
I kept telling myself
I shouldn't miss Myeong-su's mistake.
That mindset probably gave me the victory.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE: 2
TEAM SNU IN STEM: 0
He beat the second player's disadvantage.
Kudos, Seung-hyeon.
Well done.
My bad. I didn't catch that.
I missed it.
There was no stopping his final move.
I felt terrible for my teammates
for adding to the pressure
with another defeat.
- Going first?
- What?
- You'll go first, right?
- Of course.
Win for us, Gang-hyeon.
All right.
The two remaining players are solid.
It's Mr. Chess and Mr. Han Jong-yun.
Anything can happen in Deathmatches.
Maybe they reserved their best players.
They could study the opponents' tactics
and crush them in the later rounds.
Are we hoping to see
Jong-yun on a rampage?
Both teams, please decide
on who will compete in Round 3.
My victory would complete
a 3-0 clean sweep for my team,
so I was determined to win.
I had to win to keep my team in the game,
so I felt more driven to concentrate.
Please come to the stage.
- Hello.
Team SNU in Medicine won
both rounds so far.
You're right.
This round could decide the match.
He's got to step up his game.
We all knew how brilliant Gang-hyeon is,
so I felt certain he would get us the win.
Because my team had done so well,
I expected to see
an overwhelming clean sweep.
As Team SNU in STEM lost Round 2,
their player will decide who goes first.
I'll go first.
Please place a piece.
Going for the center again.
I bet Seo-yeon has a counter.
You have 30 seconds left.
HAN SEO-YEON'S DEFENSE
I say Seo-yeon has a solid game plan,
and Gang-hyeon adapts his
to counter her moves.
Adaptability is
every STEM student's middle name.
It's all about rearranging pieces now
since they don't have any good openings.
The more I watch the game,
the more important the second layer seems.
She has to defend that spot.
All pieces have been placed.
Good, that's our only option.
GANG-HYEON TURNS A PIECE UPRIGHT
Things are getting heated
for the second layer.
Nothing stands out to me.
I don't see anything, either.
She has to turn a piece.
There's no other choice.
That's her only option.
She has to keep turning pieces.
Nothing strikes me as a compelling move,
but I feel hesitant to comment.
What if one move turns out to be pivotal?
I think you need to look five moves ahead
before reaching a decision.
I did consider making a change first,
but I couldn't risk losing,
so I opted for a conservative approach.
He made the right choice.
He has to if he wants to win.
If he loses, he's going home.
This could be it for his team.
He has to win.
- Both are being cautious.
- It's a Deathmatch.
We were just as cautious
in our Deathmatch.
She can keep at it
and wait for him to mess up.
- She can strike then.
- Sure.
She's not moving any of the pieces
she placed on top of Gang-hyeon's.
We can't afford to lose this time.
It didn't seem like I could win
with the endless deadlock.
So I decided to break it with a surprise.
He's trying something.
Gang-hyeon took a gamble.
She can move the piece far up the board.
He can't try anything there.
- You're right.
- See? She's going to win in two turns.
If Seo-yeon moves the highlighted piece
as shown on screen
and lays the next piece flat
on her next turn,
she can complete her five-cell block.
- Come on.
- Please catch that.
- Come on, girl.
- You have five seconds left.
She saw it.
There we go.
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S 5-CELL BLOCK
I felt a rush of relief.
Actually, I left the center open
at one point.
HAN SEO-YEON CLAIMED THE CENTER
And she never moved that piece afterward.
I thought I had to reclaim it to win,
so I lured her into taking it away.
Gang-hyeon took a gamble.
HIS PLAN WORKED
When my trick worked,
I felt convinced I could win.
KIM GANG-HYEON TOOK THE CENTER RIGHT AWAY
Team SNU in STEM's Kim Gang-hyeon
completed a five-cell block.
Only he could've pulled off
that masterstroke.
As expected from the chess master.
How clever.
Team SNU in STEM's Kim Gang-hyeon
won Round 3 of Block Connect Five.
We'll have to prime you for Round 5.
- Get ready for another round.
- Of course.
It's going as I planned.
Older members covering
for the younger members.
- I'm so sorry for missing the final move.
- It's okay.
I was grateful that I won.
I hoped Jong-yun would win Round 4
so I could secure our survival in Round 5.
I messed up.
I got so caught up
in looking for possible attacks
that I missed the implication
of Gang-hyeon's move.
I was very disappointed.
We'll now begin Round 4
of the Deathmatch, Block Connect Five.
Players competing in Round 4
are Team SNU in STEM's Han Jong-yun
and Team SNU in Medicine's Kim Min-seok.
Please come to the stage.
As Team SNU in Medicine lost Round 4,
their player will decide who goes first.
I'll go first.
Team SNU in Medicine's Kim Min-seok
will go first.
Please place your piece.
- He needs to seal that spot.
- Yeah, then we're good.
Okay, so far, so good.
It's over, isn't it?
You bet. He's unstoppable now.
He wins with a block over there.
Oh, it's over.
With a block here,
BECAUSE OF THE 4-CELL BLOCK
it's over.
Suppose that Jong-yun built
a four-cell block in this turn.
If Min-seok places a piece
flat on the board for defense,
Jong-yun can layer a piece over it
and complete his five-cell block.
This is identical to the winning move
Min-seo used in Round 1.
JONG-YUN USED
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S TACTIC AGAINST THEM
TEAM SNU IN STEM'S 4-CELL BLOCK
Wow, we're getting the fifth round.
That was dynamite.
I thought, "What a relief. I won."
Things were literally falling into place.
They can use this to finish up
before we turn our pieces.
Let's say they tried this.
PREPARING FOR EVERY POSSIBILITY
- Right.
- How's this for defense?
- I see. A wall works.
- Right?
We can just build a wall.
When it comes to the game plans
as the first player...
Unless our opponent chose
the best move ten times in a row,
we had a surefire way to defeat them.
I knew we wouldn't lose when going first.
- He needs to build a wall.
- Exactly.
He needs that wall now.
- What's this?
- That's insane.
I can't believe it.
This was the sole viable move.
He survived that. He's not going down.
- So that's one way to defend it.
- Looks that way.
There we go.
Things are going as we practiced.
So far, so good.
Team SNU in STEM's Han Jong-yun
will now take his turn.
You have 30 seconds left.
He's basically declaring
that he will turn this next.
He has to turn this.
JONG-YUN'S SOLE MEANS OF DEFENSE
He can't just yet.
He can't turn his piece.
- He can't.
- Right.
He hasn't placed all five pieces yet.
1 PIECE STILL REMAINS
Excellent use
of the first-player advantage.
Min-seok did a great job.
The first player moves a piece first, too.
Okay, so we have
our four-cell block, right?
YOU CAN GET A 4-CELL BLOCK
BY ROTATING THE HIGHLIGHTED PIECE
- If they don't block here...
- What's our next play?
- Why not place a piece here?
- Good idea.
- It's over.
- We win.
Since we start turning first.
Take advantage
of that first-player premium.
Guys, we won.
Min-seok can turn a piece first.
ONCE JONG-YUN PLACES HIS PIECE,
MIN-SEOK CAN COMPLETE A 5-CELL BLOCK
I realized I won.
I felt relieved
and glad that I managed the game well
according to our strategy.
You have ten seconds left.
HAN JONG-YUN PLACES HIS FINAL PIECE
Team SNU in Medicine's Kim Min-seok
will now take his turn.
completed a five-cell block.
TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE'S 5-CELL BLOCK
I messed up big time.
- That was amazing.
- We might not have survived this.
The med guys mastered strategies
for going first.
They had it in the bag.
Team SNU in Medicine's Kim Min-seok
won Round 4 of Block Connect Five.
Good job.
Well done.
You don't seem happy at all.
As a fellow SNU student,
I felt bad for the STEM team.
I guess that was a killer.
The initial move they stuck with.
We didn't see it coming, either.
We thought you were going to win.
I felt so terrible for my team.
I couldn't help blaming myself.
I couldn't quite believe...
that our journey came to an end.
That concludes the Deathmatch,
Block Connect Five.
The third team to be eliminated
from Elite League Season 3 is
Team SNU in STEM.
Team SNU in STEM, please exit the grounds.
Defeat them all in our place.
Good job, guys.
I planned on surviving
with Gang-hyeon as our MVP.
You did your part, but we didn't.
I felt so sure we won Round 4.
My heart started racing.
Since the show's name is "Elite League,"
I braced myself
like an athlete in a competition.
I'll log my tile set.
That was how I felt going in.
The whole experience was closer
to a celebration
rather than a competition.
I was so happy here.
Honestly speaking,
I expected a better outcome.
I'm sad because it seems like
my mistake cost my team's survival.
While we didn't get to be the champions,
we made invaluable friends on the show.
That was amazing.
- He delivered!
- Oh, man.
I'm getting a dopamine rush.
I'd like to say I have no regrets
because I gave it my all.
I'll miss everything from the show.
It's a shame we didn't get to go higher.
Still, my teammates and I made
great memories during the last four days.
I'm glad for that.
I'd like to thank the other teams
for the amazing and fun experience.
I loved it.
Are you nervous?
I'm controlling it.
I've never been
in a competition like this.
STEM Division's Ace player is
Team SNU's Song Myeong-su.
I had fun playing so many different games
with my teammates.
I hope we can still be great friends
back on campus.
That was hilarious.
Lastly,
we have Team KAIST
representing all STEM students.
I'll keep rooting for them until the end.
NO GOOD WISHES FOR TEAM SNU IN MEDICINE,
YOUR FELLOW SNU STUDENTS?
Good luck, Team SNU in Medicine!
We wanted to say goodbye
to Team KAIST at the very least.
Did you hear us cheering for you?
- We felt it.
- Good.
The surviving three teams,
please head to your base camps.
What's this about, anyway?
What now?
- What have we got here?
- What on earth?
SPECIAL MEAL TO BOOST
THE SEMIFINALISTS' STAMINA
They prepared extra healthy food for us.
Guys, look at this.
- These are meal kits.
- "Braised abalone and oxtail"?
"I would've gotten into SNU
if I'd eaten this before my CSAT."
That's possible. This is super healthy.
Let's dig in.
- Thank you for the meal.
- Braised oxtail.
- I love this.
I've never tried this before.
It's your first-ever oxtail.
FIRST BITE OF BRAISED OXTAIL
It's great.
I can't wait to try the meat.
Seriously...
- It's unbelievable.
- They look tasty.
I can't believe these are meal kits.
Let me try the abalone.
Go ahead.
It's huge.
- It's gigantic.
Jinx.
It's crazy. The abalone tastes wonderful.
I'll try the perilla oil noodles.
- The perilla oil is so aromatic.
- It's insanely good.
We need good fats
for our brains to function faster.
Foodie YouTubers always do this.
- He's enjoying it.
- Indeed.
It's actually good, though.
It's so good.
I should ask my mom to get me these.
Buy it yourself with the prize money.
There's no need to go to your mother.
I'll do as you say.
The main match for the semifinal is
Secret Student Club.
- What?
- A reasoning game?
Similar to Find My Personality Type
from Season 1?
Probably.
Please go to the Club Rooms.
The whole setup makes me feel
like I'm on campus.
Will we get a talent show?
- I'll dance if it's an option.
- Really?
Gosh, thank you.
I'm in a band,
a drama club, and a dance club.
- Seriously?
- Yes.
You're the full package.
Let's wipe out that club's members.
Please state the club and the rank
of the person whose identity you deduced.
They are a member of the band.
What?
What are they doing?
We might end up
with Team KAIST on the throne.
Marking Team SKKU alone
might not be the best course of action.
Let's wait for the bodies to pile up
before we pounce.
Subtitle translation by Jeongwoo Kim